Seth Fleet

sethfleet@hotmail.com
www.linkedin.com/in/seth-fle
et-a15b4019

Analytics and insights professional with experience in marketing, digital analytics and consultancy. Expertise in using data to transform business questions into action that improve business performance. Able to work independently or with stakeholders from problem definition through to technical implementation and delivery. Genuine enjoyment in helping others through data, regardless of difficulty and technical approach. Naturally collaborative and curious, with a growth mindset and a love of learning.

Employment history

Jan 2020 - Present: Senior Insight Analyst, RAC

- Working across the business to identify and deliver data led insights that improve business performance.
- Achieved £400k additional revenue per year by using email engagement metrics to define flash sale contact strategy that reduced the risk of blacklisting by email service providers.
- Added 1pt to net promoter score by predicting vehicle breakdowns most likely to result in long wait times and identify customers to receive differentiated update communications.
- Demonstrated 1.7pp churn reduction benefit from a differentiated web experience for existing members.
- Developed customer lifetime model to identify opportunities for differentiated actions based on value.
- Identified and built a novel process to understand relationships between online and offline behaviour.
- Modeled historical promotional performance to maximise in-year EBITDA on future promotions.
- Identified optimal locations for new RAC approved garages based on customer blackspots.
- Built propensity model to identify customers most likely to default on payment and target comms.
- Analysis of customer digital behaviour at renewal to identify marketing and website improvements.
- Delivery at pace in a fast moving commercial organisation.

Feb 2019 - Dec 2019: Head of Insights & Analytics, Trueology

- Led the organisation's analytical function, working across the full range of clients, harnessing data to shape business decisions through actionable insights.
- Worked across the project lifecycle to understand client objectives and project deliverables, engineer analytical data sets, conduct analysis and present results. Quality control of all analytical outputs.
- Notable outputs: Attitudinal segmentation and profiling, deriving product renewal rates, forecasting acquisition and cancellation volumes, and interactive analytical dashboards.
- Moved the analytics team to a code-based approach utilising version control to support delivery to a growing and increasingly diverse client base.
- Management and development of analytical colleagues.

Sep 2018 – Dec 2018: Principal Data Scientist, UCAS

- Led the Publications team within the Analysis & Insights business unit.
- Setting and leading the technical work of my teams across analytical projects.
- Researched and applied appropriate analytical methods to deliver on projects.
- Publication of written analytical reports and web-based dashboards to enhance organisational reputation and create public benefit.
- Led the analysis and publication of reporting of unconditional offer making patterns by UK HE providers.

Jan 2014 – Sep 2018: Lead Data Scientist, UCAS

- Leading data science teams to provide research, surveys and analysis of university application data.
- Developed an analytical service from concept to deployment to robustly evaluate outreach activities.
- Implemented a new multi-dimensional equality metric to measure equality of UK HE representation.
- Introduced new web-based interactive visualisations to improve the accessibility of publicly available information on university admissions.
- Other notable projects: Understanding university applicants' decision making behaviours; Forecasting future demand for higher education; Matching students to courses using qualifications.

Jun 2008 - Dec 2013: Analyst, Higher Education Funding Council for England

- Quantitative analysis to inform sector wide policy decisions.
- Evaluation of government funded outreach programmes to encourage progression into university.
- Led the development and publication of a key higher education participation measure used across the sector, including a new web-based interactive mapping tool.

Aug 2001 – May 2008: Research Scientist, QinetiQ

Member of the Pattern and Information Processing unit, deployed across multiple research projects focussed on demonstrating the practical capabilities of machine learning algorithms for optimisation, image processing, speech recognition and condition monitoring.

Knowledge and skills

Analytical: Naturally strong analytical skills. Ability to critique existing solutions and proposals to

understand strengths and weaknesses and suggest next steps in a business context. Detail focussed but able to identify strategic analytical opportunities and capitalise using

appropriate methods.

Technical: Experienced in many areas of analytics such as exploratory data analysis, predictive

modeling, A/B and statistical hypothesis testing, clustering and data visualisation. Able to

query data to prepare extracts for cleaning and further analysis using a variety of

platforms including R, SQL, SAS (Base certified) and Alteryx.

Communication: I Understand the importance of communication in analytical roles, and can synthesise

information to form a narrative that ensures key messages are understood. Confident presenter with experience of presenting to journalists, key decision makers and technical and non-technical audiences. Excellent report writing skills having authored various high

profile analytical publications.

Management and leadership:

Proven ability to work with stakeholders to understand requirements, define technical programmes of work, and ensure the delivery of agreed objectives. I believe in fostering

a collaborative environment for my teams. Encourage others to take ownership of their

work and set stretch targets to aid professional development.

Agile methods: Undertook VFQ Product Management training which covered agile methods specific to

product development. Frequently use knowledge from this course in my approach to

project delivery.

Education

2005 – 2007: MSc Statistics (Distinction), University of Sheffield. 2 year part-time distance learning

including research project 'Simulation and Modeling of Animal Territories using R'

1998 – 2001: **BSc (Hons) Geophysical Sciences (1**st), University of Leeds.